Thong Yong Quan, Danny

Singapore | LinkedIn | 98456880 | dannyyqthong@gmail.com |

Executive Summary

As a Product Analyst, I worked closely with the product manager and business team to identify and prioritize product use cases, including time series financial and default data of various regions. I developed dashboards and visualizations using POWER BI/Excel, such as heatmaps and time series, to track product performance against competitors. I also utilized Python for data ETL with various financial vendor data and optimized the QA process using Python, improving daily efficiency by around 20%

Skill Expertise

Python, SQL, POWER BI, Business Intelligence, Data Analytics, ETL, Google Docs, AWS, Microsoft Excel, Microsoft PowerPoint, FactSet, Financial statements, <u>Financial Modeling</u>, Financial Analysis, Discounted cash flow

WORK EXPERIENCE

CriAT - FinTech Spin-Off Company from the National University of Singapore

Singapore Jan 2022-Oct 22

Product Analyst

Worked closely with product manager and business team to identify and prioritize product use cases such as time

- series financial and default data of various regions.
 Develop dashboards and visualizations using POWER BI/Excel such as heatmap & time series for product use cases &
- Extracted financial transaction data from MYSQL and used it to identify patterns and trends to support product use cases and visualization.
- Utilized python for data ETL with various financial vendor data before modeling new product features.
- Controller for daily product QA and partner with external vendors to resolve any suspicious/outlier's financial data.
 - Optimized QA process using python to improve daily efficiency by around 20% by regulating specific certain countries and economy size.

EFG BANK Singapore

Central Desk assistant

May 2020 - Feb 2021

- Reports to the deputy CEO and assists the relationship managers in areas such as PR/KYC matters with a targeted turnover of 1 day per request from relationship managers/officers at an almost 100% rate
- Accomplished a 1-month short stint as per management entreaty to assist the operations team in the turnover of opening business accounts by 20%

Private banking support manager

Nov 2019 – Apr 2020

Performed first level of quality assurance and review for new client onboarding and periodic review

Free-lance Research assistant to TMT research director

Singapore

Free-Lance equity research

Jun 2018 - Aug 2019

- Constructed quarterly and annual financial and valuation models to estimate future revenue growth, earnings, and
 profitability such as using APPLE's 1Q16 to 4Q18 historical performance to forecast APPLE's next few quarterly financials
- Evaluated SEC reports, 10-K, 10-Q, and 8-K, to determine past trends and trends outlook and create detailed financial models of companies such as FAANG group, HAI DI LAO, PINDUO, NIUNIU, Tencent

Julius Baer Private Banking

Singapore

Compliance Officer

Apr 2018 – Apr 2019

 Acts as advisory support to the business to resolve newly identified KYC issues and full PR such as source of wealth, transaction monitoring, client screening which increase accounts completion efficiency time by at least 20%

Deloitte Singapore

Client due diligence executive

Jun 2017 – Aug 2017

 Validated internal audit such as transaction monitoring, suspicious transaction review, CDD & KYC regulations requirements, sanctions, source of wealth report & corroboration hitting daily KPIs of 4 accounts and exceeding

Standard Chartered Private Banking

Singapore

Client due-diligence Analyst

Nov 2016 – May 2017

• Guarded against fraud, including impersonation, and identity fraud, within market segments such as India, Indonesia, Malaysia, Dubai, Hong Kong, and Singapore, and turnover of 1 day for assigned urgent accounts

Professional Certificate

FINANCIAL MODELING AND VALUATION ANALYST CERTIFICATE

 Developed an <u>Interactive Financial Model of NETFLIX</u> using DCF valuation with sensitivity/scenario with a potential 10-15% downside

BUSINESS AND DATA ANALYTICS - BCG RISE PROGRAM

- Built a business model via excel, using targeted market and analysis aiming to increase APPLE's iPhones revenue from -3% to 11%
- Designed and developed different kinds of dashboards using POWER BI & provided insights to improve the manufacturing efficiency by at least 20%
- Developed a human-centric designed project on SAFE ENTRY check-in process to increase the turnover time by at least 15% while aiming to reduce user's frustrations
- Utilized AWS CLOUD with python and machine learning to improve PSA's port efficiency achieving MEAN ABSOLUTE PERCENTAGE ERROR of 3.xx% via linear regression & Random Forest Regression

IBM DATA SCIENCE PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATE

- Coursera-based program covers Python & SQL, including machine learning modeling skills with Python
- Predicted house prices via a linear regression model for housing prices achieving 0.7 R^2
- Built a machine learning model to predict SPACEX FALCON 9 success launches utilizing python libraries such as Pandas, NumPy's, BeautifulSoup, Matplotlib

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF LONDON INTERNATIONAL PROGRAMS

Singapore

Banking and Finance(honors)

NGEE ANN POLYTECHNIC

Singapore

Business process and quality management

INTERESTS

Interests: Basketball, Esports, Casual Gaming, Travelling, Dogs, Karaoke, Music, Technology